{"header":"INFORMATION FOR PARTICIPANTS","intro":"We invite you to participate in the Register to be Registered (R2R) program, also known as the Registry, coordinated by Australian and New Zealand Congenital Heart Consortium. You can consent to participate yourself provided you are 18 years of age or older. If you are not 18 years of age yet you can still participate with the consent of a parent or guardian. Before you do, it is important that you understand what is involved and what will be done with the information you provide. This information document contains answers to some of the questions you might have. At the end of the form there is a section for you to sign to confirm that you agree to participate. If you have any questions after reading this form, please contact the coordinators of R2R using the contact details provided later in this information document before signing the form. This project has been approved by the South Western Sydney Local Health District (SWSLHD) Human Research Ethics Committee.","consent":"You can electronically fill in and sign the consent form yourself provided you are 18 years of age or older. If you are under 18 years of age then you may also sign the consent form, and additionally your parent or guardian will need to provide their signed consent for your participation.","consentcontent":["I consent to having my information stored in the Register to be Registered Database and for non-identifiable information to be transferred (in a form identifiable only by a code) for research and publication.","I agree to receive follow-up contact from the Registry organisers, in order to keep my record and the Registry up to date, or to follow-up on any queries about the information I have previously entered.","If there are any major changes in my data (for example change of address or changes in my medical condition) that occur in the period between updates, I agree to inform the Registry."],"disclaimercontent":[{"question":"What is a patient registry and why would you want to participate in one?","answer":"A Registry is a centralised data set. 'Register to be Registered' is considered a vital first step program to achieving a nationwide Congenital Heart Disease Registry. The Registry aim is to collect data from all people in Australia living with a previously diagnosed Congenital Heart Disease, also known as (CHD) diagnosis, regardless of the current status of their disease condition. Some participants may not be aware that their condition is known as a Congenital Heart Disease condition. This may be the case for participants previously diagnosed with a heart murmur for example. If you believe you may fit the CHD criteria, even if you have not had surgery as a child or adult to correct this condition, we would ask that you still consider participating in this registry program as you will quite possibly fit the criteria of a person with a CHD. This first program is considered necessary to achieving the overall goal of an Australia CHD Registry as it will facilitate the ability to capture not only adults and adolescents who have transitioned from childhood care to adult care, but also children currently living with a current or corrected CHD."},{"question":"Whose data is being collected in this registry?","answer":"This Registry is for individuals living with a previous diagnosis of CHD. Examples of previous diagnosis included in The Registry are:","list":["Atrial Septal Defect (ASD)","Ventricular Septal Defect (VSD)","Patient Ductus Arteriosus","Coarctation of the Aorta","Aortic Valve Disease","Pulmonary Valve Disease","Mitral Valve Disease","Atrio-ventricular septal defects (AVSD)","Tetralogy of Fallot","Transposition of the Great Vessels","Pulmonary Atresia","Single Ventricle pathology","Cyanotic Congenital Disease"]},{"question":"What information is being collected and why?","answer":"The Registry will contain demographic information about you including: name, date of birth, sex, post code, state, phone number, email address, your ethnicity, country of birth and language spoken. Some of this information is called identifiable information and will be stored in a secure and confidential manner in order to prevent you from being identified by anyone other than those directly involved with the Registry. The Registry will also contain information about your previous diagnosis including the specific name of your diagnosis, if you have ever received surgery to correct that original diagnosis, the timeliness of the care you believe you received, the current care you may be receiving today, how the diagnosis and follow-up care has impacted your day to day living, educational impact questions, costs of managing your disease and how you consider your quality of care overall in dealing with your diagnosis has been delivered to date. The information in the Registry will allow us to provide you with new information relevant to standards of care for your condition, offer potential opportunities for follow-up with specialist in your area but ultimately provide us with a better understanding of the burden of diagnosis from childhood to adulthood."},{"question":"Who should fill in this form?","answer":"If you are the participant, you can fill in and sign the form yourself, provided you are 18 years of age or older. If you are under 18 years of age but can understand this information, you may consent, but we will also require your parent or guardian to consent with you. Whatever your age, please discuss registration with your family and don’t hesitate to contact us if you have any questions. If you are the parent or guardian of a child who is not old enough to understand this form, please consent if you want your child’s data to be included in the Registry via the 'Carer' option on the previous screen by selecting 'disagree' below first."},{"question":"Who will be able to access the data within the Registry?","answer":"Only specific people within the Registry are given authority to access identifiable data. Your data will be stored in a re-identifiable form.     Selected data (non-identifiable) about all participants will be made available for research purposes or for health policy development purposes. This type of information will consist only of the information you have provided that does not identify you, but characterises your diagnosis and how you were cared for then and now. The research purposes may involve publishing information on the incidence of CHD in Australia, publishing information on the access to services in Australia, or perception of care received by people living with a CHD diagnosis. Examples of policy development purposes may include presentation of data to local or federal government to support policy changes or funding arrangements to hospitals. It is not know for certain what all purposes may be at this time, however each purpose will be governed by the overseeing ethics committee for this program."},{"question":"How long will my data be kept?","answer":"The data in the Registry will be maintained indefinitely. If the Registry closes down or ceases to function, then all records held within the Registry will be stored in a secure setting by the national curator for a period of 7 years or less and then destroyed by the electronic destruction methods in place at that time."},{"question":"How will my privacy be protected?","answer":"The Registry is a stored electronic record of a participants personal and clinical experiences. This file will be subject to the regulations on data protection, , at both state and national levels, and we will only transfer under national laws1,2. Any information we collect in the Registry that can identify you will be treated as confidential. We will be permitted disclose identified information only with your permission, except as required by law. All confidential information shall be encrypted and stored securely, in accordance with each state’s and national privacy laws.If we publish any research or other documents based on data from the registries, this research will never identify you by name. Third parties wishing to have access to data in the Registry (such as researchers for publication purposes, or companies planning clinical trials or conducting research on new treatments) will only have access to information identifiable by a code. That means that it is non-identifiable back to you. Before they are granted access even to this coded information, they must have the approval of a Human Research Ethics Committee. The Registry will not be made available to employers, government departments, insurance companies or educational institutions, however there may be occasion where non-identifiable information is prepared as described above and presented to third parties for policy change initiatives. Your information will remain confidential except in the case of a legal requirement to pass on personal information to authorised third parties. This requirement is standard and applies to information collected both in research and non-research situations. Such requests to access information are rare; however we have an obligation to inform you of this possibility."},{"question":"Who will have access to my medical records?","answer":"Nobody within this Registry program will have access to your medical records. The only information that will be available in this Registry is information that you have provided and consented to its use by the Registry coordinators. In the event that the scope of this Registry extends and it is intended to obtain more information about your clinical experience, we would contact you and request additional consent to be able to access medical records. This consent would only be sought freely from you and you would be able to decline further participation if that was your decision."},{"question":"How will I be identified in The Registry?","answer":"Your personal details (name, address, etc) have to be stored in the Registry so that we can contact you if required in the future. This data will be stored in a secure manner and your records will be assigned a unique code. If we transfer your data to any third party, including any other disease registry, we will not transfer any of your personal details, and your records will only be identifiable by the code they have been assigned. Only the coordinators of the Registry or a person explicitly appointed by the coordinators will be able to 'de-code' the data to get access to your personal details."},{"question":"How can I update my data if it changes?","answer":"We will need to review data in the Registry regularly, to ensure that it is up to date. You can assist us by updating us at any time you consider required by logging in and making changes. Aspects which may change more frequently would be your contact details for example."},{"question":"How will I benefit from registering?","answer":"The Registry is intended as a public service for the benefit of patients living with a previous diagnosis of CHD. You will not receive any payment or any other financial benefit as a result of submitting your data to the Registry. The results of research facilitated by the Registry may have commercial potential. However, you will not receive financial benefits from future commercial development. Nevertheless, there may be other benefits to participating, including the following: The data collected might also provide benefits to other patients with your condition, for example by revealing statistics on how many people in Australia have the same condition, or providing information for researchers interested in the best standards of care for your condition. We will publish some general statistical information from the Registry on our website."},{"question":"Do I have to participate in The Registry and can I withdraw if I change my mind?","answer":"Your participation in this project is completely voluntary. The Federal Privacy Act and associated principles and guidelines1,2 grants you the right to rectify your data or withdraw from further participation in the Registry at any time. Should you wish to withdraw from the Registry you will be free to do so without having to provide any explanation. Once you withdraw your existing records will be maintained in the Registry unless you request that they be destroyed. Once you withdraw you will not be contacted further by the Registry organisers. If you wish to withdraw, you should get in touch with the staff in charge of the Registry. Contact details are provided below."},{"question":"Who should I contact if I have any questions?","answer":"If you would like any additional information, need to tell us about any change in your data, or if you wish to withdraw your data from the Registry, please contact the person from the state in which you live listed in the contact table at the end of this form. Human Research Ethics Committee Reference Details"}]}